Finding Aid for Dentistry Library (University of Michigan) records, 1925-2006
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Dentistry Library (University of Michigan) records 1925-2006, 1960-1997
University of Michigan. Dentistry Library.
12.5 linear feet
2014126 Bimu C430 2
The Dentistry Library Collection contains papers pertaining to the library as it served the School of Dentistry collecting books, journals and theses for research and reference use. Items of interest include: annual reports, library statistics, course materials, rare book information, and media clippings on faculty and staff.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record group was received from the School of Dentistry - Dentistry Library (Donor Number 764 ) in three accessions in June 1998, June 2008, and July 2008.
Periodic additions to the records are expected.
The collection is open to research.
A College of Dental Surgery was established at the University of Michigan in 1875. Shortly thereafter, it was announced that, "a library of dental science will be speedily supplied" (General Catalogue 1876-1877, page 139). The library was originally in the Dean's office and consisted of books and dental journals donated by professors, alumni, and interested professionals. The original collection was not cataloged and no librarian or attendant was employed.
In 1893, Corydon L. Ford donated his collection of crania to the college and the library also took on a museum role. A second collection of over 500 osseous specimens were received from Drs. William and L.J. Mitchell in 1904. This resulted in the library splitting into two collections: the Dr. Jonathan Taft Dentistry Library, named after the first Dean of the school and the Ford-Mitchell Museum, named after its founding donors.
The library moved into larger facilities when the College of Dental Surgery acquired its new building in 1908. The dental faculty petitioned the U-M Board of Regents to allow for a library fee to be collected from dental students to support collection development and a part-time attendant. In 1910, a part-time professional bibliographer was employed to organize and catalog the Dental Library's collection. (U-M Regent's Proceedings, November 1910).
In 1918, Dentistry Dean Marcus Ward made the somewhat controversial decision to turn the Dental Library over to the General Library's custody in order to better develop the library with full-time staff and "expert service." In 1928, the library and museum separated and the museum collection was turned over to U-M's Museum of Paleontology.
The Dentistry Library was a recipient of a Carnegie Foundation library grant in 1929 which provided five years of funding to develop a model dental library. Inez Bowler took charge of the project and by 1933 the library had 6,000 volumes cataloged in the Library of Congress classification system.
The library continued to grow and space quickly became an issue in the old building. In 1969, the library moved to temporary quarters in a newly constructed wing of the School of Dentistry while the old Dentistry Building was demolished to make way for another new wing. Construction was completed and the library moved into its new space in 1971. The 1980s saw the institution of the University Library's online catalog MIRLYN and also the medical database MEDLINE. The library continued to expand and eventually outgrew its facility at the School of Dentistry. The Dentistry Library joined the Health Sciences Library group in 1963 and thus was under the purview of the Taubman Medical Library. The library and its collection were absorbed by the Taubman Medical Library in June 2008, which was renamed in April 2010 as the Taubman Health Sciences Library.
Department/Program Heads
1923-1925 Margaret Kirkpatrick
1925-1929 Elana Taylor
1929-1934 Inez Bowler
1934-1939 Marjorie Lewis
1939-1954 Hilda Rankin
1954-1960 Rose-Grace Faucher
1961-1965 Ellen Theurer Hall
1966-1996 Susan Seger
1996-1998 Doreen Bradley
1998-2008 Pat Anderson
The Dentistry Library Collection contains papers pertaining to the library as it served the School of Dentistry collecting books, journals and theses for research and reference use. Items of interest include: annual reports, library statistics, course materials, rare book information, and media clippings on faculty and staff. The University of Michigan Dentistry Library Collection is divided into four series, which reflect the structure of the library itself: Administrative, Library Collection, Library Services, and Clippings Files.
Subjects:
Dentistry--Michigan.; Libraries--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; University of Michigan. Dentistry Library.; University of Michigan. School of Dentistry.; University of Michigan--Students.
- Administrative 1930-2006
  The Administrative series, 1930-2006 (2.5 linear feet), contains papers dealing with the administrative side of the library. This includes: annual reports, library statistics, budget, committees, staffing information, and unit goals.
  - Association of Academic Health Sciences Library Directors (AAHSLD) Surveys 1984-1991 (Box 1)
  - Base Budget 1996-1998 (Box 1)
  - Budget Reallocation 1989-1990 (Box 1)
  - Budget Reallocation 1992-1993 (Box 1)
  - Budget Reallocation 1995-1996 (Box 1)
  - Budget Reductions 1980 (Box 1)
  - Budget Requests 1956-1986 (Box 1)
  - Building and Equipment Management 1969-1975 (Box 1)
  - Building and Equipment Management 1984-1997 (Box 1)
  - Building Emergency Guidelines 2006 (Box 1)
  - CAIDENT and Dentistry Library Merger 1997 (Box 1)
  - Center for Information Resources and Community Learning Enterprises (CIRCLE) 1996, 2000 (Box 1)
  - Collection Budget Request Documents 1997-1998 (Box 1)
  - CSCAR Workshop on Meta-Analysis 2004 (Box 1)
  - Dentistry Collection Mutilation 1994 (Box 1)
  - Dentistry Library Annual Report 1930-1995, 4 folders (Box 1)
  - Dentistry Library Blueprints 1967 (Box 1)
  - Dentistry Library Collection and Usage Expenditures 1993-1995 (Box 1)
  - Dentistry Library Committee 1962-1998 (Box 1)
  - Dentistry Library Informatics Collaboration 2006 (Box 1)
  - Dentistry Library Mission and Strategic Plan 1996 (Box 1)
  - Dentistry Library Statistics 1999-2005 (Box 1)
  - Draft Report of the Task Force on Instructional Computing undated (Box 1)
  - Electronic Exit Control and Tattle Tape 1977 (Box 1)
  - Emergency Procedures and Facilities Management for the Health Science Cluster of the University of Michigan Libraries 1997 (Box 1)
  - Endowment 1991 (Box 1)
  - Evaluation Report by the Commission on Dental Accreditation 1995 (Box 1)
  - Gift Forms and Policy 1992 & 1998 (Box 1)
  - Gifts and Donors 1966-1982 (Box 1)
  - Health Sciences Cluster Alfred Taubman Medical Administration 1991-1992 (Box 2)
  - Health Sciences Cluster Annual Report 1992-1993 (Box 2)
  - Health Sciences Cluster Annual Reports of the Dental, Public Health, and Taubman Medical Libraries 1990-1992, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Library Committee 1997 (Box 2)
  - Library Information for Accreditation of the School of Dentistry 1970 & 1978 (Box 2)
  - Library Information for Accreditation of the School of Dentistry 1985-1991 (Box 2)
  - Library Information for Accreditation of the School of Dentistry User Surveys 1994-1995 (Box 2)
  - Library Information for National Directories 1993-1999 (Box 2)
  - Monthly Reports 1985-1989, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - National Library of Medicine Grant Application for Medline 1992-1994 (Box 2)
  - National Library of Medicine Grant Application for Outreach 1991 (Box 2)
  - National Library of Medicine Medical Library Resource Grant 1966-1970 (Box 2)
  - Pat Anderson Information Management Issues for Dentistry Lecture undated (Box 2)
  - Patron Count and Request to Change Hours 2003 (Box 2)
  - Personnel Files 1961-1977 (Box 2)
  - Proposal for a Learning Commons in a Dental School: A Collaboratory of the Dentistry Library, CAIDENT, and the Office of Dental Informatics 2005-2006 (Box 2)
  - Quarterly Reports 1989-1992 (Box 2)
  - School of Dentistry General Information 1995-1996 (Box 2)
  - School of Dentistry Transition Committee 1987-1989 (Box 2)
  - Sindecuse Dental Museum 1991-1992 (Box 2)
  - Staff Position Descriptions 1995-1996 (Box 2)
  - Technical Processing Manual undated (Box 2)
  - Travel Request Forms 1995-1996 (Box 2)
  - Unit Goals 1981-1996, 10 folders (Box 2)
  - University Library Planning 1992-1998 (Box 3)
  - University Library and Dentistry Library Strategic Plans 1994-1996 (Box 3)
  - University of Michigan Dentistry Library Operations Manual 2001 (Box 3)
  - University of Michigan School of Dentistry Accreditation Survey Form 1960 (Box 3)
  - University of Michigan School of Dentistry Faculty, Staff, and Student Policy on Alcohol and other Drugs 1994 (Box 3)
  - Ward Library and Memorial Funds 1989-1998 (Box 3)
- Library Collection 1925-1997
  The Library Collection series, 1925-1997 (6.5 linear feet), has information on items in the Dentistry Library's collection. In some cases, as with the bound course materials, the series houses items that were in the library's collection. This series includes a list of School of Dentistry theses from 1987-1995. The series has a sub-series, Course Material which includes bound copies of: sample student examinations, course materials, and student term papers. Courses particularly represented through the student term papers include: Dental Radiology, Partial Denture Seminar, Prenatal Facial Growth, and Postnatal Facial Growth.
  - General
    - Chalmers J. Lyons Memorial Collection 1948 (Box 3)
    - Conservation 1997 (Box 3)
    - Dental Thesis List 1987-1995 (Box 3)
    - Dentistry Library Historical Materials 1925-1980 (Box 3)
    - "History of College of Dental Surgery University of Michigan, 1875-1925" circa 1925 (Box 3)
    - Marcus L. Ward Notes and Comments on the Dental Library 1955 (Box 3)
    - Michigan Dental M.S. Thesis Listings 1879-1963 circa 1963 (Box 3)
    - Rare Book Correspondence 1930-1996 (Box 3)
    - Rare Book Collection 1930-1989 (Box 3)
    - Rare Book and Special Collections at the University of Michigan Report 1996 (Box 3)
  - Course Materials 1941-1982
    - Cell Biology Student Report Dent 671 1966 (Box 3)
    - Complete Denture 724 1971 (Box 3)
    - Dental Hygiene Anatomy Exams 1955-1970 (4 Bound Volumes) (Box 3)
    - DPH 520 Term Papers, Winter 1982 (Box 3)
    - DPH 622 Term Papers, Winter 1980 (Box 3)
    - DPH 625 Term Papers, Winter 1981 (Box 3)
    - Postnatal Facial Growth Term Papers 1963-1967 (5 Bound Volumes) (Box 4)
    - Prenatal Facial Growth Term Papers 1962-1967 (6 Bound Volumes) (Box 4)
    - Prenatal Facial Growth Term Papers 1968-1973 (6 Bound Volumes) (Box 5)
    - School of Dentistry Freshman Year Examinations 1957-1968 (2 Bound Volumes) (Box 5)
    - School of Dentistry Sophomore Year Examinations 1957-1970 (4 Bound Volumes) (Box 5)
    - School of Dentistry Junior Year Examinations 1958-1968 (2 Bound Volumes) (Box 6)
    - School of Dentistry Senior Year Examinations 1958-1968 (3 Bound Volumes) (Box 6)
  - Student Term Papers -- Bound 1941-1972
    - Akerly, William B., The Roentgenographic Evaluation of Bone as Related to Prosthodontics January 9, 1963 (Box 6)
    - Allen, Don L., Nuclear Control of Protein Synthesis April 30, 1964 (Box 6)
    - Alling, Charles G., Repair of Fractured Mandible January 1952 (Box 6)
    - Aronis, Constantine B., The Determination of Vertical Dimension and Centric Relation by Means of Cranial Roentgenology January 14, 1961 (Box 6)
    - Ash, Major M., Dental Applications of Atomic Energy and Dental Radioautography December 30, 1951 (Box 6)
    - Barrancos, Ricardo J., The Psychology and Physiology of Pain May 1964 (Box 6)
    - Bear, S. Elmer, The Treatment of Mandibular Fractures with the External Pin Fixation and Open Reduction with Transosseous Wires undated (Box 6)
    - Benson, David, The Mucostatic Principle April 17, 1969 (Box 6)
    - Blankenship, John R., An Evaluation of Inter-occlusal Records using Gothic Arch Tracings versus Wax Records April 21, 1969 (Box 6)
    - Blankenship, John R., Terminal Hinge Axis, "O," 1, or 2. Complete Denture Seminar 1968 (Box 6)
    - Boucher, Daniel J., The role of the Orthodontist and Radiography in the Treatment of Traumatized Teeth January 15, 1952 (Box 6)
    - Boyd, T. K., Reasons for a Radiographic Examination of all Edentulous Patients undated (Box 6)
    - Braaten, C. R., The Detection, Treatment, and Prognosis of Young Incisors whose Roots have been Fractured September 29, 1954 (Box 6)
    - Bradbury, David R., Orthopantomograph Investigation 1966 (Box 6)
    - Bucher, John F., A Study of the Hazards of X-Ray Radiation in the Dental Office: Methods to Minimize these Hazards January 1958 (Box 7)
    - Cain, Martin, Jr., Radiographs Used in the Diagnosis of Traumatic Occlusion 1955 (Box 7)
    - Carson, John B., Can Developmental Prognosis for the Cleft Palate Patient be Improved if Surgical Interception is Postponed until Four or Five Years of Age? 1958 (Box 7)
    - Cardoso, Oswaldo Santos, Protection in Dental Radiography undated (Box 7)
    - Castro, Maria Elena, Major Trigeminal Neuralgia undated (Box 7)
    - Chaudhry, K. P., The Necessity for Routine Roentogenographic of the Prosthetic Patients: A Review of Literature November 23, 1960 (Box 7)
    - Clayton, Joseph A., Electronic Strain Gauges in Dental Research December 4, 1964 (Box 7)
    - Clayton, Joseph A., The Reliability of Roentgenograms December 15, 1964 (Box 7)
    - Cohen, John, Periapical Radiographic Technique: Its Evolution and analysis January 1960 (Box 7)
    - Cohen, Philip William, Internal Resorption: A Review of the Literature December 1966 (Box 7)
    - Collier, Durward R., The Developmental Prognosis of the Cleft Palate Patient when Surgical Intervention has been Delayed until Four or Five Years of Age 1958 (Box 7)
    - Cook, James E., What is the Cause of the Hyper-nasality and Defective Articulation of the Speech of the Person with a Cleft Palate? January 10, 1958 (Box 7)
    - Corpron, Richard E., Radiographic Interpretation of Cysts of the Jaws January 6, 1958 (Box 7)
    - Crocker, George L., A Comparison between Normal Speech and the Speech of the Un-operated Cleft Palate Patient, with a Consideration of the Cause of Hypernasality and Faulty Articulation January 10, 1958 (Box 7)
    - Crockett, Clifford D., History of Local Anaesthesia undated (Box 7)
    - Crookston, Lynn B., Replantation of Teeth June 6, 1949 (Box 7)
    - Cunningham, John B., The Dental Involvement of Maxillary Sinus 1948 (Box 7)
    - Daprai, Frederick P., Hypophosphatasia: Premature Loss of Teeth March 15, 1967 (Box 7)
    - Davenport, Edward L., Personality and Behavior Development from Infancy through School Age Children May 1964 (Box 7)
    - De Vries, Stan, The Enigmatic Union of the Premaxilla and Maxilla at the Ectofacial Surface December 1964 (Box 7)
    - DeChamplain, Richard W., Radiology in the Treatment of Oral Cancer 1962 (Box 7)
    - DePass Jiminez, Ronald, The Structure and Functional Importance of the Meniscus of the Temporomandibular Joint 1963 (Box 7)
    - Dietz, Anthony R., Reliability of Roetgenograms in Endodontics December 1965 (Box 7)
    - Dietz, Gerald C., Dental Radiology and the Law January 1960 (Box 7)
    - Doezema, S. T., The Influence of Impression Procedures on Base Stability in Removable Partial Dentures 1973 (Box 7)
    - Ebel, Henry E., Radiographic Evaluation of Tissue Changes Around Abutment Teeth January 16, 1959 (Box 7)
    - Ebmeyer, Gerald, The Relation of Age to Attrition and Spacing of the Primary Dentition undated (Box 7)
    - Eder, Melvyn, The Need for Routine Full Mouth Radiographic Examination of Dental Patients May 1957 (Box 7)
    - Eifert, Donald F., The Effect of Surgery on Growth of the Maxilla and Eruption of Teeth in a Cleft Palate Child January 10, 1958 (Box 7)
    - Eiser, Harold. A Historical Review of the Development and Adoption of a Dental Health Program for Children by the American Dental Association 1969 (Box 7)
    - Engler, William O., The Specificity and Reliability of Tritiated Thymidine Radioautography undated (Box 7)
    - Evanson, Leonard, The Use of Stereoroentgenography in Determining Pulpal Anatomy January 1960 (Box 7)
    - Fastlicht, Jorge, Contributions of Dr. Allan G. Brodie to Orthodontics July 1963 (Box 7)
    - Fausto, Duenas M., Keratinization of Oral Mucous Membranes April 30, 1964 (Box 7)
    - Feinzaig, Jaime, Development of the Articulator 1971 (Box 7)
    - Frost, John R., The Importance of Roentgenographic Examination of the Edentulous Patient January 1955 (Box 7)
    - Garber, Fred, Radioluscent Periapical Areas 1960 (Box 7)
    - Gibbons, Paul, Roentgenography from the Point of View of the Prosthodontist: A Review of the Literature May 20, 1949 (Box 7)
    - Gibson, Ronald M. E., Panoramic Radiography 1965 (Box 7)
    - Gilson, C. Mark, Blood Dyscrasias of Dental Significance undated (Box 7)
    - Gilson, C. Mark, The Dentist and the Diabetic undated (Box 7)
    - Gold, Stephen L., Resistance to Departments of Community Dentistry in Dental Schools December 9, 1960 (Box 7)
    - Gonzalez, Juan B., Osteoradionecrosis of the Jaws January 19, 1962 (Box 7)
    - Goodkind, Richard J., Radiology and the Edentulous Patient January 10, 1963 (Box 7)
    - Graves, R. C., An Evaluation of the Effectiveness of the Elementary School Teacher as a Dental Health Educator December 4, 1968 (Box 7)
    - Green, Edward N., Investigation of the Use of Contrast Media in Root Canals January 1956 (Box 7)
    - Green, Molly Ann, Malignant Oral Tumors of Infancy and Childhood March 10, 1967 (Box 7)
    - Gullett, W. Irwin, The Value of Routine Roentgenograms of the Edentulous and Partially Edentulous Mouth undated (Box 7)
    - Hagan, Edmund H., Can the Developmental Prognosis for the Cleft Palate Patient be Improved if Surgical Intervention is Postponed until Four to Five Years of Age? 1958 (Box 7)
    - Halhoul, Nagi M., Roentgenography and Dental Caries January 10, 1963 (Box 7)
    - Hall, D. L., Radiology and Orthodontics undated (Box 7)
    - Hall, Walter A., Insufficient Mastication undated (Box 7)
    - Johnson, Gary W., Post-Insertion Changes with Removable Partial Dentures December 15, 1972 (Box 8)
    - Johnson, R. E., Radiography in Diagnosis and Treatment of Osteomyelitis of the Jaws undated (Box 8)
    - Johnston, Harry B., Jr., Endocrine Disorders: Their Manifestations in Dental Radiology May 1947 (Box 8)
    - Jordan, David R., The Place of X-Rays in Evaluation of Temperomandibular Disturbance January 1959 (Box 8)
    - Justi, William H., The Problem of Dental Lesions as Possible Foci of Systemic Infection undated (Box 8)
    - Kanar, Henry L., Measurements for Abnormal Behavior from Birth through Twelve Years of Age April 1969 (Box 8)
    - Kaufman, Myron, Eosinophilic Granuloma of Bone: With Report of Case Involving the Maxilla and Mandible undated (Box 8)
    - Kaya, Kazumasa, X-Ray Contrast Media undated (Box 8)
    - Kelly, James F., A Simplified Technique for 35mm Reproduction of Radiographs January 28, 1960 (Box 8)
    - Kepron, D., Some Aspects of Velopharyngeal Closure: A Radiographic Study January 1955 (Box 8)
    - Kiester, Gordon L., General Principles in Management of Facial Fractures undated (Box 8)
    - Kirsten, Maurice, A Study of Ligature Wires and their Application undated (Box 8)
    - Kirstine, W. D., Radiology: Its Importance in Orthodontic Practice 1955 (Box 8)
    - Kobayashi, Lloyd, The Experimental Production of Cleft Palate with Cortisone January 11, 1963 (Box 8)
    - Kopel, Hugh M., The Use of Medicaments in the Sterilization of Deep Cavities, Fall 1947 (Box 8)
    - Le May, Louis Philippe, Radiology: An Aid in Fixed Partial Prosthesis December 12, 1966 (Box 8)
    - Lee, Russell H., The Variability of Rest Position March 1969 (Box 8)
    - Lemeh, Dorotha, An Examination of Federal-State Dental Public Health Programs for Disadvantaged Children, Fall 1968 (Box 8)
    - Lovely, Franklyn Willard, Cellular Alterations Associated with Anti-folic Chemotherapy April 1964 (Box 8)
    - Luna, Cristobal, Behavior of Non-vital Teeth and Surrounding Tissues as Abutments of Bridges and Partial Dentures January 22, 1959 (Box 8)
    - Lutz, Bernard L., Group Practice in Dentistry in the United States: A Review of the Scientific Literature December 4, 1968 (Box 8)
    - Lynch, Burton, Principles of Radiation Therapy undated (Box 8)
    - Maher, Joseph F., Radiological Interpretation of Anatomic Structures in the Posterior-anterior Cephalogram January 13, 1954 (Box 8)
    - Mann, William R., Acrylic and Styrene Resins June 2, 1941 (Box 8)
    - Mann, William R., The Heat Treatment of Ticonium June 4, 1941 (Box 8)
    - Massey, Katherene M., Chemical Modification of the Effects of Ionizing Radiation: The Use of S,2-Aminoethylisothiuronium Bromide Hydrobromide 1963 (Box 8)
    - Mathers, H. M., An Introduction to Biologic Tracer Methodology April 1964 (Box 9)
    - McIntosh, Carolyn S., Barriers to the Utilization of Local Dental Care Facilities by Low-Income Urban Groups December 4, 1968 (Box 9)
    - Mickler, Arthur M., Diabetes Mellitus and Dentistry January 1950 (Box 9)
    - Mickler, Arthur M., Siliceous Cement, Cavity Liners and Varnishes: Their Effect on the Dental Pulp January 1950 (Box 9)
    - Miller, Sidney L., Age-Specific Embryological Review of Oro-Facial Clefts, Fall 1957 (Box 9)
    - Mohorn, Harold Wayne, The Cementoma December 1966 (Box 9)
    - Morawa, Arnold P., A Classification of the Anomalies of Form and Structure of the Dentition December 11, 1964 (Box 9)
    - More, Frederick G., The Role of Desoxyribonucleic Acid in the Transmission of Hereditary Characteristics April 1969 (Box 9)
    - Munoz, Fernando, The Value of Roentgenographic Study of Edentulous Mouths 1961 (Box 9)
    - Nakamoto, Tetsuo, The Effect of Prosthetic Appliance on Unerupted Teeth in the Maxilla and Mandible undated (Box 9)
    - Nolla, Carmen M., A Complete Composite Type of Odontoma: A Case Report undated (Box 9)
    - Novetsky, Marvin, The Third Point of Reference, Winter 1970 (Box 9)
    - Panzer, Milton, The Endocrine Glands as Related to Growth and Development of the Teeth undated (Box 9)
    - Panzer, Milton, The Heat Produced During Cavity Instrumentation undated (Box 9)
    - Petty, Charles R., Salivary Calculi 1950 (Box 9)
    - Pinson, Thomas J., Roentgenographic Examination to Determine the Accuracy of Mandibular Block Injection Techniques undated (Box 9)
    - Porritt, John L., Oral Radiographic Manifestations of Systemic Disease undated (Box 9)
    - Rainey, Bernard L., Wound Healing April 30, 1964 (Box 9)
    - Ramirez, Walter A., Panoramic Laminagraphy December 1964 (Box 9)
    - Ray, R. Richard, The Fine Structures of the Dental Pulp April 30, 1964 (Box 9)
    - Reynolds, Richard L., The Biochemistry and Morphology of the Cancer Cell April 30, 1964 (Box 9)
    - Reynolds, Richard L., Bisecting-Angle and Parallel Radiographic Techniques December 1964 (Box 9)
    - Richards, Robert D., The Arrangement and Positioning of Teeth May 20, 1949 (Box 9)
    - Robinson, L. D., Roentgenographic Celphalometrics in Denture Prosthesis 1964 (Box 9)
    - Roffinella, John P., Diagnosis of Ameloblastoma 1951 (Box 9)
    - Rohrich, P. G., Endocrines as Related to Orthodontics 1948 (Box 9)
    - Rosenast, E. O., Jr., The Third Molar Tooth in Man, Fall 1950 (Box 9)
    - Rudy, Leon C., The Importance of Dental Radiographs in the Diagnosis of Systemic Disease January 21, 1958 (Box 9)
    - Russman, Sumner A., Use of Medicated or Germicidal Cements in the Practice of Dentistry, Fall 1946 (Box 9)
    - Sauer, John L., Roentgenocinematography and some Dental Uses January 1963 (Box 9)
    - Sawusch, Raymond H., Why Should a Speech Therapist want the Tonsils and Adenoids Preserved in Some Children with Cleft Palate January 10, 1958 (Box 9)